<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Pasza's blog</title><link>/</link><description>Recent content on Pasza's blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Piotr Pasza Storożenko</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 04 Sep 2021 11:01:14 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Pizza Twice as Big 🍕</title><link>/posts/pizza-twice-as-big/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Sep 2021 11:01:14 +0200</pubDate><guid>/posts/pizza-twice-as-big/</guid><description>
One morning I was standing in a queue in my local bakery, and I&amp;rsquo;ve seen a woman buying one of those small quasi-pizzas. Pizzas ~20cm in diameter. Immediately I thought about how profitable it is when compared to the full-size 42cm pizza. Since the area of a larger pizza is 4 times bigger, of course, it&amp;rsquo;s not worth buying smaller pizzas.
Then I thought about fitting smaller pizzas inside the bigger one.</description></item><item><title>Comparing fractions of fractions on COVID case 😷</title><link>/posts/comparing-fractions-of-fractions/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Aug 2021 21:38:08 +0200</pubDate><guid>/posts/comparing-fractions-of-fractions/</guid><description>
I had a little argue recently with one anti-vaxxer and I thought it will make an interesting blog content. I tried to convince them that vaccinating is good because people are at least not dieing and what I&amp;rsquo;ve heard was:
Ohh, vaccines are not helping at all. A friend of mine is working at the hospital at says that 50% of covid patients were already vaccinated.
I decided not to argue nor check the data source, but rather give it a try.</description></item><item><title>My First Post!</title><link>/posts/my-first-post/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Aug 2021 23:51:46 +0200</pubDate><guid>/posts/my-first-post/</guid><description>
Hello, my name is Pasza /ˈpaʃa/ and I welcome you to my blog. My plan is to share with you many insights I find on interesting topics. Some will be probably understandable for primary school kids and some will require university level math. This is however my blog and I can do what I want ^^.
You can find more about me in related pages. As for now you can check out useful materials.</description></item><item><title>About me</title><link>/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/about/</guid><description>
Hi, my name is Piotr Pasza Storożenko located in Warsaw, Poland. I&amp;rsquo;m a data scientist, physicist, by heart with love for programming. Wannabe applied mathematician. A huge julia enthusiast, but I code mostly in python and R. Some small chunks of code and simulations in C++17 and newer are also fine ^^. On this blog I share things I find interesting.
GitHub: pstorozenko LinkedIn Piotr Storożenko Experience:
2021 - now ML Engineer@Appsilon 2020 - 2021 Data Scientist@ING Bank Śląski Summer 2019 Research internship SURF@IFISC, UIB, Palma de Mallorca Summer 2017 Internship in Advanced NLP Group@Samsung R&amp;amp;D Education:</description></item><item><title>Useful materials</title><link>/useful-materials/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/useful-materials/</guid><description>
Here I present some resources I found very useful when learning various stuff:
Youtube channels I know that because of youtube I was able to see a lot of different experiment that I only heard about during my classes in high school. It kept my curiosity at high level and encouraged me to study physics. During my studies I understood various concepts only because of brilliant content creators from youtube. Here I pay my small tribute to some of my favorite scientific videos creators.</description></item></channel></rss>