<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>math on Pasza's blog</title><link>/tags/math/</link><description>Recent content in math on Pasza's blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Piotr Pasza Storożenko</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Sep 2021 07:33:51 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/math/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Leuven Ring Problem ◯‍</title><link>/posts/leuven-ring-problem/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Sep 2021 07:33:51 +0200</pubDate><guid>/posts/leuven-ring-problem/</guid><description>
During my studies, I spent one semester at KU Leuven. There is one interesting mathematical problem from those times I&amp;rsquo;d like to share. This Belgian city has a topology of a big circle with a city inside.
One early, cold, damp, and windy morning (as it is in Belgium) when I was coming back from some trip I had to go from the railway station (right side of the ring) to my dormitory (bottom of the ring).</description></item><item><title>Pizza Twice as Big 🍕</title><link>/posts/pizza-twice-as-big/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Sep 2021 11:01:14 +0200</pubDate><guid>/posts/pizza-twice-as-big/</guid><description>
One morning I was standing in a queue in my local bakery, and I&amp;rsquo;ve seen a woman buying one of those small quasi-pizzas. Pizzas ~20cm in diameter. Immediately I thought about how profitable it is when compared to the full-size 42cm pizza. Since the area of a larger pizza is 4 times bigger, of course, it&amp;rsquo;s not worth buying smaller pizzas.
Then I thought about fitting smaller pizzas inside the bigger one.</description></item><item><title>Comparing fractions of fractions on COVID case 😷</title><link>/posts/comparing-fractions-of-fractions/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Aug 2021 21:38:08 +0200</pubDate><guid>/posts/comparing-fractions-of-fractions/</guid><description>
I had a little argue recently with one anti-vaxxer and I thought it will make an interesting blog content. I tried to convince them that vaccinating is good because people are at least not dieing and what I&amp;rsquo;ve heard was:
Ohh, vaccines are not helping at all. A friend of mine is working at the hospital at says that 50% of covid patients were already vaccinated.
I decided not to argue nor check the data source, but rather give it a try.</description></item></channel></rss>