<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>machine-learning on Pasza's blog</title><link>/tags/machine-learning/</link><description>Recent content in machine-learning on Pasza's blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Piotr Pasza Storożenko</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 29 Nov 2021 16:18:26 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/machine-learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Detecting Solar Panels from satellite images part 2 -- machine learning in fastai 🤖</title><link>/posts/solar-panels-2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Nov 2021 16:18:26 +0100</pubDate><guid>/posts/solar-panels-2/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="/posts/solar-panels-1">As mentioned a month ago&lt;/a>, I write a series of posts on detecting solar panels from satellite images at my company, &lt;a href="https://appsilon.com">Appsilon&lt;/a>.
In this post I focus on using &lt;code>fastai&lt;/code> python library to deliver a working ML model in few hours!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Detecting Solar Panels from satellite images part 1 -- data preparation🛰️</title><link>/posts/solar-panels-1/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Nov 2021 11:18:26 +0100</pubDate><guid>/posts/solar-panels-1/</guid><description>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m writing a series of posts on detecting solar panels from satellite images at my company, &lt;a href="https://appsilon.com">Appsilon&lt;/a>.
To be honest, not from satellite images but from &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Orthophoto">orthophotos&lt;/a>.
If you don&amp;rsquo;t know what are orthophotos, the good news is that &lt;a href="https://appsilon.com/using-ai-to-detect-solar-panels-part-1/">the first post has been released recently!&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>ML Data Versioning With DVC: How to manage machine learning data 🗃</title><link>/posts/ml-data-versioning-with-dvc/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Oct 2021 07:23:26 +0200</pubDate><guid>/posts/ml-data-versioning-with-dvc/</guid><description>
Recently I wrote a post about DVC at my company&amp;rsquo;s, Appsilon blog. DVC is like a git, but for data, models and experiments. It also allows for creating an automated experiments pipelines.
As a teaser I&amp;rsquo;ll just say that, having prepared scripts for model training and evaluating, when new data is added to the repo, the whole training is run automatically. Metrics are saved to appropriate files alongside with parameters, same with plots.</description></item></channel></rss>