<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on Pasza's blog</title><link>/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on Pasza's blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Piotr Pasza Storożenko</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Nov 2021 21:34:30 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Square Root √2 Pizza Box</title><link>/posts/square-root-pizza/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Nov 2021 21:34:30 +0100</pubDate><guid>/posts/square-root-pizza/</guid><description>
Today I have a short one, a follow-up to the post on pizza sizes. Recently, I was in my local pizza place where I had to choose between 32 and 46cm pizza. The bigger one cost 5 PLN more. Even without looking at my table, I chose the bigger one. I knew, however, that I&amp;rsquo;m going to eat only half of my pizza so I asked to pack the remaining half.</description></item><item><title>Practical Mathematical Optimization 🏡🛒🧃</title><link>/posts/practical-mathematical-optimization/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Nov 2021 14:18:35 +0100</pubDate><guid>/posts/practical-mathematical-optimization/</guid><description>
&lt;p>In &lt;a href="/posts/mathematical-optimization/">the previous post&lt;/a> I&amp;rsquo;ve presented the basics of stating mathematical optimization problems and JuMP framework in julia.
Today let&amp;rsquo;s follow up with concrete examples!
Please checkout &lt;a href="https://github.com/pstorozenko/pstorozenko.github.io/blob/main/code/practical-mathematical-optimization/main.ipynb">the accompanying jupyter notebook&lt;/a> even though you might not feel like a programmer.
It&amp;rsquo;s very clear and shows how easy it is to obtain solutions!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Introduction Into Mathematical Optimization Way of Thinking 🧮</title><link>/posts/mathematical-optimization/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Nov 2021 19:40:13 +0100</pubDate><guid>/posts/mathematical-optimization/</guid><description>
In the post about fitting pizzas inside another pizza I&amp;rsquo;ve shown the following picture and promised a post about recreating it.
Pizzas packed in pizza However, I would not like to assume that everyone is familiar with the optimization theory (you may graduate from Computer Science and still not know a lot) so I want to present an introduction here as high school math and quadratic equations are enough to understand those concepts.</description></item><item><title>Detecting Solar Panels from satellite images part 1 -- data preparation🛰️</title><link>/posts/solar-panels-1/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Nov 2021 11:18:26 +0100</pubDate><guid>/posts/solar-panels-1/</guid><description>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m writing a series of posts on detecting solar panels from satellite images at my company, &lt;a href="https://appsilon.com">Appsilon&lt;/a>.
To be honest, not from satellite images but from &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Orthophoto">orthophotos&lt;/a>.
If you don&amp;rsquo;t know what are orthophotos, the good news is that &lt;a href="https://appsilon.com/using-ai-to-detect-solar-panels-part-1/">the first post has been released recently!&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How to Sum Like a Boss (Almost) Σ</title><link>/posts/how-to-sum-like-a-boss/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Oct 2021 08:42:59 +0200</pubDate><guid>/posts/how-to-sum-like-a-boss/</guid><description>
&lt;p>In a recent post, I presented how memory layout may influence a matrix summing speed.
It&amp;rsquo;s interesting to see that there are plenty of pitfalls we might fall into when writing sum function and memory layout is not the only one.
Please first &lt;a href="/posts/speed-of-traversing-matrix/" title="Post on summing by rows vs cols first">read the previous post on summing&lt;/a> if you haven&amp;rsquo;t already.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Without thinking &lt;em>why&lt;/em>, let&amp;rsquo;s take a look at those two functions:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>ML Data Versioning With DVC: How to manage machine learning data 🗃</title><link>/posts/ml-data-versioning-with-dvc/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Oct 2021 07:23:26 +0200</pubDate><guid>/posts/ml-data-versioning-with-dvc/</guid><description>
Recently I wrote a post about DVC at my company&amp;rsquo;s, Appsilon blog. DVC is like a git, but for data, models and experiments. It also allows for creating an automated experiments pipelines.
As a teaser I&amp;rsquo;ll just say that, having prepared scripts for model training and evaluating, when new data is added to the repo, the whole training is run automatically. Metrics are saved to appropriate files alongside with parameters, same with plots.</description></item><item><title>Speed of Traversing Matrix → vs ↓</title><link>/posts/speed-of-traversing-matrix/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2021 22:24:55 +0200</pubDate><guid>/posts/speed-of-traversing-matrix/</guid><description>
Today I would like to mention a low-level peculiarity I was taught in highschool, but passed over during my studies.
Why it differs whetter matrix is traversed by rows or columns? Even though we think of a matrices as a two dimensional creatures, inside a computer they have to be stored as a sequence of numbers. Therefore there are two schemas one can follow, row-first and column-first. Historically they are called C-style and Fortran-style respectively.</description></item><item><title>The Leuven Ring Problem ○</title><link>/posts/leuven-ring-problem/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Sep 2021 01:33:51 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/leuven-ring-problem/</guid><description>
During my studies, I spent one semester at KU Leuven. There is one interesting mathematical problem from those times I&amp;rsquo;d like to share. This Belgian city has a topology of a big circle with a city inside.
One early, cold, damp, and windy morning (as it is in Belgium) when I was coming back from some trip I had to go from the railway station (right side of the ring) to my dormitory (bottom of the ring).</description></item><item><title>Pizza Twice as Big 🍕</title><link>/posts/pizza-twice-as-big/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Sep 2021 11:01:14 +0200</pubDate><guid>/posts/pizza-twice-as-big/</guid><description>
One morning I was standing in a queue in my local bakery, and I&amp;rsquo;ve seen a woman buying one of those small quasi-pizzas. Pizzas ~20cm in diameter. Immediately I thought about how profitable it is when compared to the full-size 42cm pizza. Since the area of a larger pizza is 4 times bigger, of course, it&amp;rsquo;s not worth buying smaller pizzas.
Then I thought about fitting smaller pizzas inside the bigger one.</description></item><item><title>Comparing fractions of fractions on COVID case 😷</title><link>/posts/comparing-fractions-of-fractions/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Aug 2021 21:38:08 +0200</pubDate><guid>/posts/comparing-fractions-of-fractions/</guid><description>
I had a little argue recently with one anti-vaxxer and I thought it will make an interesting blog content. I tried to convince them that vaccinating is good because people are at least not dieing and what I&amp;rsquo;ve heard was:
Ohh, vaccines are not helping at all. A friend of mine is working at the hospital at says that 50% of covid patients were already vaccinated.
I decided not to argue nor check the data source, but rather give it a try.</description></item><item><title>My First Post!</title><link>/posts/my-first-post/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Aug 2021 23:51:46 +0200</pubDate><guid>/posts/my-first-post/</guid><description>
Hello, my name is Pasza /ˈpaʃa/ and I welcome you to my blog. My plan is to share with you many insights I find on interesting topics. Some will be probably understandable for primary school kids and some will require university level math. This is however my blog and I can do what I want ^^.
You can find more about me in related pages. As for now you can check out useful materials.</description></item></channel></rss>