<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>julia on Pasza's blog</title><link>/tags/julia/</link><description>Recent content in julia on Pasza's blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>Piotr Pasza Storożenko</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Jan 2022 21:00:59 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/julia/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Minimizing The Sum of Absolute Values -- Day 7 Advent of Code part 1 🎄</title><link>/posts/aoc2021-minimizing-loss/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Jan 2022 21:00:59 +0100</pubDate><guid>/posts/aoc2021-minimizing-loss/</guid><description>
This year I took part in the advent of code event. If you&amp;rsquo;ve never heard about it, I attach tl;dr bellow. Today, I&amp;rsquo;d like to share my solution for Day 7 problem, because I find it very interesting.
In the first half of the post I describe comparison in time complexity of two solutions (programming). In the second half I outline the proof of one solution (math). What is the Advent of Code # For sure you had some kind of advent calendar in the past (or you still have), e.</description></item><item><title>Practical Mathematical Optimization 🏡🛒🧃</title><link>/posts/practical-mathematical-optimization/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Nov 2021 14:18:35 +0100</pubDate><guid>/posts/practical-mathematical-optimization/</guid><description>
&lt;p>In &lt;a href="/posts/mathematical-optimization/">the previous post&lt;/a> I&amp;rsquo;ve presented the basics of stating mathematical optimization problems and JuMP framework in julia.
Today let&amp;rsquo;s follow up with concrete examples!
Please checkout &lt;a href="https://github.com/pstorozenko/pstorozenko.github.io/blob/main/code/practical-mathematical-optimization/main.ipynb">the accompanying jupyter notebook&lt;/a> even though you might not feel like a programmer.
It&amp;rsquo;s very clear and shows how easy it is to obtain solutions!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Introduction Into Mathematical Optimization Way of Thinking 🧮</title><link>/posts/mathematical-optimization/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Nov 2021 19:40:13 +0100</pubDate><guid>/posts/mathematical-optimization/</guid><description>
In the post about fitting pizzas inside another pizza I&amp;rsquo;ve shown the following picture and promised a post about recreating it.
Pizzas packed in pizza However, I would not like to assume that everyone is familiar with the optimization theory (you may graduate from Computer Science and still not know a lot) so I want to present an introduction here as high school math and quadratic equations are enough to understand those concepts.</description></item><item><title>How to Sum Like a Boss (Almost) Σ</title><link>/posts/how-to-sum-like-a-boss/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Oct 2021 08:42:59 +0200</pubDate><guid>/posts/how-to-sum-like-a-boss/</guid><description>
&lt;p>In a recent post, I presented how memory layout may influence a matrix summing speed.
It&amp;rsquo;s interesting to see that there are plenty of pitfalls we might fall into when writing sum function and memory layout is not the only one.
Please first &lt;a href="/posts/speed-of-traversing-matrix/" title="Post on summing by rows vs cols first">read the previous post on summing&lt;/a> if you haven&amp;rsquo;t already.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Without thinking &lt;em>why&lt;/em>, let&amp;rsquo;s take a look at those two functions:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Speed of Traversing Matrix → vs ↓</title><link>/posts/speed-of-traversing-matrix/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2021 22:24:55 +0200</pubDate><guid>/posts/speed-of-traversing-matrix/</guid><description>
Today I would like to mention a low-level peculiarity I was taught in highschool, but passed over during my studies.
Why it differs whetter matrix is traversed by rows or columns? # Even though we think of a matrices as a two dimensional creatures, inside a computer they have to be stored as a sequence of numbers. Therefore there are two schemas one can follow, row-first and column-first. Historically they are called C-style and Fortran-style respectively.</description></item><item><title>Pizza Twice as Big 🍕</title><link>/posts/pizza-twice-as-big/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Sep 2021 11:01:14 +0200</pubDate><guid>/posts/pizza-twice-as-big/</guid><description>
One morning I was standing in a queue in my local bakery, and I&amp;rsquo;ve seen a woman buying one of those small quasi-pizzas. Pizzas ~20cm in diameter. Immediately I thought about how profitable it is when compared to the full-size 42cm pizza. Since the area of a larger pizza is 4 times bigger, of course, it&amp;rsquo;s not worth buying smaller pizzas.
Then I thought about fitting smaller pizzas inside the bigger one.</description></item></channel></rss>